<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Events on Golang Estonia</title><link>https://golangestonia.github.io/events/</link><description>Recent content in Events on Golang Estonia</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://golangestonia.github.io/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting Started</title><link>https://golangestonia.github.io/events/2020-10-28-delta/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://golangestonia.github.io/events/2020-10-28-delta/</guid><description>We held our first Tartu meetup in the new Delta building. The full event can be seen at UTTV.
&amp;ldquo;Philosophy of Go&amp;rdquo; by Egon Elbre Egon Elbre gave an overview of the philosophy of Go and how to approach programming in Go.
&amp;ldquo;Getting Started with Go&amp;rdquo; by Marko Kungla Marko Kungla gave a thorough overview of where to get started and what to look out for in Go.</description></item><item><title>Error Handling</title><link>https://golangestonia.github.io/events/2020-06-29-remote/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://golangestonia.github.io/events/2020-06-29-remote/</guid><description>We held our third event online. The full event can be seen on Youtube.
&amp;ldquo;Error Handling&amp;rdquo; by Vitalii Lakusta Vitalii Lakusta gave a through overview of error handling in Go.
Recording, Slides
Demo &amp;ldquo;Diagramming&amp;rdquo; by Egon Elbre Egon Elbre demonstrated https://github.com/loov/diagram for creating diagrams in Go.
Recording
Demo &amp;ldquo;Djinni format&amp;rdquo; by Masakazu Ohtsuka Masakazu Ohtsuka demonstrated parsing he wrote https://github.com/planetway/djinni-renderer.
Recording</description></item><item><title>Simple, WASM and Performance</title><link>https://golangestonia.github.io/events/2020-02-05-mooncascade/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://golangestonia.github.io/events/2020-02-05-mooncascade/</guid><description>Our second meetup was held at Mooncascade.
&amp;ldquo;Stupid Simple!&amp;rdquo; by Vladimir Andrianov Vladimir Andrianov shared his excitement for Domain-Driven Design (DDD) and the simplicity of Go.
Slides
&amp;ldquo;The State of WebAssembly in Go&amp;rdquo; by Matias Insaurralde Matías Insaurralde from Paraguay shared the state of Web Assembly and Go.
Slides
&amp;ldquo;A Tale of Performant Breadth-First-Search&amp;rdquo; by Egon Elbre Egon Elbre urged us to use better algorithms, use less memory and fewer pointers for better performance (if that is what is needed).</description></item><item><title>10 Years of Go</title><link>https://golangestonia.github.io/events/2019-11-22-starship/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://golangestonia.github.io/events/2019-11-22-starship/</guid><description>We celebrated 10 years of Go with the first Golang Estonia meetup at Starship.
Go at Starship by Joel Mislav Kunst Joel Mislav Kunst shared how Go is used at Starship for their autonomous package delivery robots. Shared his experience that Go is great for performance critical components and that it&amp;rsquo;s easy to learn, but not the best for fast prototyping.
10 Years of Go by Egon Elbre Egon Elbre explained why he got fascinated with Go already in 2009 and what is the philosophy of Go.</description></item></channel></rss>